In the game of seduction, there is only one rule: Never fall in love.
Cruel Intentions is a drama, romance film directed by Roger Kumble.
Slaking a thirst for dangerous games, Kathryn challenges her stepbrother,
Sebastian, to deflower their headmaster's daughter before the summer ends.
If he succeeds, the prize is the chance to bed Kathryn.
But if he loses, Kathryn will claim his most prized possession.
Kathryn Merteuil, played by Sarah Michelle Gellar.
Sébastian Valmont, played by Ryan Phillippe.
Annette Hargrove, played by Reese Witherspoon.
Cecile Caldwell, played by Selma Blair.
Helen Rosemond, played by Louise Fletcher.
Blaine Tuttle, played by Joshua Jackson.
Cruel Intentions is a 1999 American teen romantic drama film written and directed by Roger Kumble, and
starring Ryan Phillippe, Sarah Michelle Gellar, Reese Witherspoon, and Selma Blair.
The film, set in New York City among rich high schoolers, is a modern retelling of
Pierre Choderlos de Laclos' 1782 novel Les Liaisons dangereuses.
Initially a smaller-budget independent film, it was picked up by
Columbia Pictures and widely released on March 5, 1999.
Despite mixed critical reviews, the performances of Gellar, Philippe, and
Witherspoon were praised and the film grossed $75.9 million worldwide.
Since its release, the film has become regarded as a cult classic.
Its box office success spawned a media franchise with a prequel in 2000 and a standalone
sequel in 2004, as well as a jukebox musical in 2015 and a 2024 television series.
The film explores themes of bet, virgin, drug abuse,
sibling relationship, based on novel or book.
The tone is emotional.